<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puto's Toy House</title>
    <description>My playground.</description>
    <link>http://putolaruan.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://putolaruan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving to Github Pages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After hosting this website of mine on a VPS for a year, I’ve decided to move it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.
For those who are not familiar with it, Github Pages allows you to serve either your personal, organization
or your Github project’s web pages through github itself just by having a repository on your github accounts with its repo name matching a pattern.
For personal websites like mine, the default URL would be githubaccountname.github.com.
You can then configure your DNS settings on your domain provider to point to github 
(instructions &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/about-custom-domains-for-github-pages-sites/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why move it?  For the past year, I was only using Amazon’s AWS free trial.  After that expired, I tried looking into
other VPS providers (DO, Linode, Vultr, etc.).  I almost created an instance on Vultr, but I can’t justify the expense 
since I have no plans on using it for anything other than a website.  Lastly, Github Pages uses Jekyll already, which is 
perfect since I already use it as my blogging platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;putolaruan.com will stay here for now, until I find a reason to setup my own VPS again, or if I decide to use
my Github Pages solely for my open source works (that is, if I get anything done at all!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 23:04:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/10/20/moving-to-github-pages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/10/20/moving-to-github-pages.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Racing Heart</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Racing heart, cannot stop&lt;br /&gt;
My mind is revving with just your breathing&lt;br /&gt;
Fill me up, I need it, stat&lt;br /&gt;
I can’t run out, don’t wanna finish last&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve got a few more laps till I’m over the line&lt;br /&gt;
That separates you and I&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 07:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/07/06/racing-heart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/07/06/racing-heart.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's been a while</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long while since I posted on this blog.  At first, I thought of posting here every week or so.  Sadly, I got distracted.  So here I am, trying to write about my experiences again.  Hopefully, I can devote time for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coinciding with me writing again on this blog, is me learning new things again related to web development.  Any software developer knows that you need to continue on trying out, experimenting, reading about new technologies, lest you be left behind by your peers and by the industry.  I’m looking on revisiting node.js, as well as React, and Python3.  But this time, I’ll take things slower, and try to work on little goals instead of planning one big project with the said technologies.  This ends the blog post.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 08:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/05/28/its-been-a-while.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2015/05/28/its-been-a-while.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working with legacy code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Legacy code.  Rarely do these words be met with enthusiasm amongst devs.  Most programmers would like to code something current, new, trending.  It’s understandable, it’s fun to create your own than maintaining code that has been passed to you, especially those that are considered to be out of date.  However, most devs would run into legacy code, whether they like to or not.  That’s the case for me right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I do find creating new web apps more fun than handling old, established, stable code.  You get to experiment, do rapid prototypes, proof of concepts.  It’s exciting to see something you’ve developed to mature into something beautiful (although it can grow to be a monster too).  Modifying, maintaining or fixing old systems though, is usually not.  It can be frustrating, looking through the code and trying to understand why certain things are done in certain ways.  It feels like you’re an archeologist of software.  Sometimes, even trying to make it work on your machine can be tedious due to the application using and relying on outdated versions of either the language, the database, web server, or libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 years of working, and now I get to handle &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; legacy code.  Not just hand-me-down code.  It’s quite outdated in architecture, coding style, and practices.  However, I try to be optimistic.  I believe there are ways to make this experience more appealing, and I’m sure there are challenges ahead that I can learn a lot from.  Maybe there’s a treasure I can find somewhere here while cleaning the place up.  Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 22:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/11/02/first-real-legacy-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/11/02/first-real-legacy-code.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a site for me is tedious.  I’m not great with designing web pages.  In fact, I’m utter shit.  So when I decided to have my own website, I needed to find a way to create one easily.  Nothing extravagant, but something presentable, at least.  My search lead me to Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static web site generator written in Ruby.  It’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;most popular&lt;/a&gt; one in github, in fact.  I know nothing about Ruby, but I haven’t needed the knowledge so far.  Jekyll
is quite easy to use, and the documentation is solid.  I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; format for writing my posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I still needed to design my page.  I searched for Jekyll themes and good thing there was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; that showcases some good ones.  I chose Pixyll created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://johnotander.com&quot;&gt;John Otander&lt;/a&gt;, as I feel that its simplicity is perfect for my personality.  So far, I’m satisfied with the result.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 05:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/10/03/jekyll-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/10/03/jekyll-blog.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there!  This is my first post ever on my site.  Hoping to fill this up soon with random things and ramblings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 03:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/10/03/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://putolaruan.com/blog/2014/10/03/first-post.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
